<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Service | 2i2c</title><link>https://2i2c.org/category/service/</link><atom:link href="https://2i2c.org/category/service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Service</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://2i2c.org/media/sharing.png</url><title>Service</title><link>https://2i2c.org/category/service/</link></image><item><title>Towards scalable and sustainable networks of community hubs</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/funding-community-networks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/funding-community-networks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the past several years, 2i2c has built a platform for serving community-centric hubs that provide a digital home for workflows in creating and sharing knowledge.
See
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/report-czi-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our three-year retrospective&lt;/a>
for a report about the growth and impact this service has had.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During that time, we&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with several models for funding and sustaining this infrastructure.
We&amp;rsquo;ve tried everything from direct cost-recovery from individual communities, to institutional contracts that cover several hubs, to grant-based models that fund many communities at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are pros and cons associated with each, and we believe that a combination of all of them is important for a long-term service sustainability model for 2i2c.
However, with this post we&amp;rsquo;d like to share the community funding model that strikes the right balance between short-term sustainability and scalability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short: 2i2c aims to serve &lt;strong>networks of communities&lt;/strong> that are joined by a domain or workflow, and &lt;strong>fund the network at once&lt;/strong> rather than through one-on-one contracts.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-a-model-of-the-funding-and-service-relationships-we-aim-to-build">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="A model of the funding and service relationships we aim to build." srcset="
/blog/2024/funding-community-networks/funding-diagram_huef6171770d3f945ecb769945214c72b6_199419_15fb78a5d9701ec09c6da27bef81f993.webp 400w,
/blog/2024/funding-community-networks/funding-diagram_huef6171770d3f945ecb769945214c72b6_199419_9c621de6bd73688bee874c1c42f00cc1.webp 760w,
/blog/2024/funding-community-networks/funding-diagram_huef6171770d3f945ecb769945214c72b6_199419_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/funding-community-networks/funding-diagram_huef6171770d3f945ecb769945214c72b6_199419_15fb78a5d9701ec09c6da27bef81f993.webp"
width="760"
height="357"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
A model of the funding and service relationships we aim to build.
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>We believe that this model strikes a balance between &amp;ldquo;scalable and very simple hubs&amp;rdquo; (which require a lot of administrative toil) and &amp;ldquo;fully bespoke hubs&amp;rdquo; (which are expensive and unscalable).
By using a single funding contract to serve many communities, we can reduce the amount of sales and contracting toil for each community.
This will let us raise funds more quickly, and focus more of our time on delivering service.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="we-are-seeking-community-leaders-to-collaborate">
We are seeking community leaders to collaborate
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#we-are-seeking-community-leaders-to-collaborate">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re part of one or more communities that would benefit from cloud infrastructure for creating and sharing knowledge, and believe a network like this would benefit you, please reach out!
We are seeking leaders collaborate in designing service for networks like the ones described above, and identifying potential funding sources for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in collaborating on this, send an e-mail to
&lt;a href="" >&lt;code>partnerships@2i2c.org&lt;/code>&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learn-more">
Learn more
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#learn-more">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>You can find more information about this fundraising and service strategy in
&lt;a href="https://compass.2i2c.org/partnerships/fundraising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our Team Compass documentation&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An update to 2i2c's value proposition</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/value-proposition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/value-proposition/</guid><description>&lt;p>2i2c recently finished
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/report-czi-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >it&amp;rsquo;s three year retrospective&lt;/a>
after closing out its original seed grant.
As part of this process, we&amp;rsquo;re revisiting our organizational strategy, structure, and overall plan, in order to incorporate the learning that we&amp;rsquo;ve done over our first three years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our &lt;strong>value proposition&lt;/strong> is a key framing for 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s intended impact, key stakeholders, and platform strategy.
We recently completed a team exercise to refine this statement for 2i2c, and are excited to share it with you below:&lt;/p>
&lt;style>
.pull-quote {
padding-left: 1rem;
border-left: .25rem solid #1d4ef5;
margin-bottom: 1rem;
}
.pull-title {
font-size: 1.5rem;
margin-bottom: .5rem;
font-weight: bold;
}
.pull-subtitle {
font-size: 1rem;
font-style: italic;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;div class="pull-quote">
&lt;p class="pull-title">
A global network of community hubs for interactive learning and discovery
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="pull-subtitle">
Our interactive computing platform gives your community a digital home to create and share knowledge, and a global network of communities to learn from.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This is an exciting direction that leans into and builds upon the way we&amp;rsquo;ve described our service so far.
It recognizes that the value in our service doesn&amp;rsquo;t end with simple access to an interactive computing environment, but lies in how that environment&amp;rsquo;s tools empower a community to create and share knowledge with one another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We believe that this is an exciting direction to build towards, because it is based in the value of the collection of communities we serve, and the way that this network can be greater than the sum of its parts.
We&amp;rsquo;re excited to lean into this direction in how we shape our platform, what open source contributions we make, and where we aim to have impact in the coming years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To begin, we&amp;rsquo;ve interwoven some ideas from this value proposition into 2i2c.org, and the way that we describe our service.
We&amp;rsquo;d love feedback from anyone who has an idea, a critique, or &amp;ldquo;yes, and&amp;rdquo; to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-recent-talk-with-this-value-proposition">
A recent talk with this value proposition
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#a-recent-talk-with-this-value-proposition">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As part of this work, 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s Executive Director,
&lt;a href="" >Chris Holdgraf&lt;/a>
, gave a talk about 2i2c to the
&lt;a href="https://incentivizingopen.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Incentivizing Open and Collaborative Research&lt;/a>
(ICOR) community. Here are some links in case others are interested:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1C-TNSI2h0181y6-z5tL9AWSRsWp9IfZqCDtcIZEs1MM/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Slides for viewing&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://incentivizingopen.org/2024/05/data-sharing-and-analysis-in-collaborative-open-research-environments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >More information for the talk&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/944769875#t=400s" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Video link&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the video below for quick reference:&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/944769875#t=400s?h=e0f92e7926" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/944769875">Data Sharing and Analysis in Collaborative Open Research Environments&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/user219434759">Michael Markie&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security report for jupyter-server-proxy: CVE-2024-28179</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/cve-jupyter-server-proxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/cve-jupyter-server-proxy/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-happened">
What happened?
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#what-happened">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A few weeks ago, the JupyterHub team discovered a security vulnerability in
&lt;a href="https://jupyter-server-proxy.readthedocs.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >the &lt;code>jupyter-server-proxy&lt;/code> package&lt;/a>
that would allow potential unauthenticated access to a JupyterHub via WebSockets, allowing unauthenticated users to run arbitrary code on the JupyterHub.
&lt;code>jupyter-server-proxy&lt;/code> is used by many communities to provide alternative user interfaces like RStudio and remote desktops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This vulnerability was detected by the JupyterHub team, with leadership from 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s engineers. It was resolved through upstream contributions to the JupyterHub project, and we have deployed a fix that mitigates this vulnerability for all the hubs 2i2c manages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="does-this-impact-my-2i2c-community-hub">
Does this impact my 2i2c community hub?
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#does-this-impact-my-2i2c-community-hub">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We do not believe that any of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s communities were impacted by this vulnerability, and
&lt;a href="https://github.com/2i2c-org/infrastructure/blob/f86d128a0d045163e72802f6df287a6f46d4b738/helm-charts/basehub/values.yaml#L296" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >a patch&lt;/a>
has now been pushed to all community hubs to resolve this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your community was vulnerable to this problem, you might experience slightly slower startup latency while we work out a long-term solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since this is a vulnerability in the docker image used by our communities, we will be reaching out over the next few weeks to put a more permanent fix in place.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="where-can-i-learn-more">
Where can I learn more?
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#where-can-i-learn-more">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>See
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyterhub/jupyter-server-proxy/security/advisories/GHSA-w3vc-fx9p-wp4v" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >the JupyterHub security advisory for CVE-2024-28179&lt;/a>
for more information about the security vulnerability, including details on the mitigation we have put in place to protect our communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">
Conclusion
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#conclusion">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re grateful that the JupyterHub community was quick to acknowledge, respond, and resolve this security vulnerability after it was brought to their attention.
We&amp;rsquo;re also proud that 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s engineers helped the JupyterHub team throughout the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This allowed our team to resolve the problem before it impacted any of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s communities.
Because 2i2c community infrastructure is managed in a central location, we were able to resolve this for over 80 communities with a single team rather than expecting each community to learn about and fix this problem on their own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also believe this reflects the healthy upstream relationships that we hope to encourage with our team&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href="https://compass.2i2c.org/open-source/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Open Source strategy and practices&lt;/a>
.
By working with the JupyterHub community and pushing changes upstream, we&amp;rsquo;ve resolved this issue for &lt;em>any&lt;/em> user of &lt;code>jupyter-server-proxy&lt;/code>, not just 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s own ecosystem.
In particular, because of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s position running hubs for many communities via Kubernetes, we were able to identify a solution that did not require every user image to be updated (as described in section &lt;strong>For JupyterHub admins of Z2JH installations&lt;/strong>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We believe that all of these lead to a healthier, safer ecosystem of open source tools ❤️.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>