<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Update | 2i2c</title><link>https://2i2c.org/tag/update/</link><atom:link href="https://2i2c.org/tag/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Update</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://2i2c.org/media/sharing.png</url><title>Update</title><link>https://2i2c.org/tag/update/</link></image><item><title>Refactoring Jupyter Book 2 documentation ahead of a major release</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyter-book-docs-refactor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyter-book-docs-refactor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Documentation is what turns open source code into products that people actually want to use. We recently spent a few days refactoring the
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/jupyter-book/" >Jupyter Book&lt;/a> documentation to prepare for the upcoming Jupyter Book 2 release, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited about how much clearer the docs have become!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-we-did">
What we did
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#what-we-did">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We restructured the docs using the
&lt;a href="https://diataxis.fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Diataxis framework&lt;/a> to better organize content by user type and task:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reorganized into clear topic areas with landing pages for easier navigation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added missing content like the feature voting table and contributing guides&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created upgrade guidance to help users understand the relationship between Jupyter Book 2 and MyST&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This work helps users find what they need faster and gives the project a stronger foundation to build on going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-were-excited-about-it">
Why we&amp;rsquo;re excited about it
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#why-were-excited-about-it">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Better documentation reduces maintainer burden by helping users answer their own questions, and it makes the project more welcoming and useful to new contributors. We hope this makes Jupyter Book more accessible to everyone and lays a good foundation for the new release!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re also excited because so many others helped provide edits and comments!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learn-more">
Learn more
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#learn-more">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyter-book/jupyter-book/pull/2422" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >PR implementing the refactor&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyter-book/jupyter-book/blob/next/docs/contribute/docs.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Documentation principles we developed&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://next.jupyterbook.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jupyter Book 2 documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Thanks to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/rlanzafame" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >@rlanzafame&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/FreekPols" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >@FreekPols&lt;/a>, and
&lt;a href="https://github.com/bsipocz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >@bsipocz&lt;/a> for their helpful reviews, edits, and feedback on the PR!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/pythia/" >Project Pythia&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/cryocloud/" >CryoCloud&lt;/a>, and the Berkeley educational projects are our primary member communities using MyST and
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/jupyter-book/" >Jupyter Book&lt;/a>. Their support covers the cost of these kinds of foundational contributions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Our Product and Service goals for Q3 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/q3-goals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/q3-goals/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we enter Q3 2025, our focus remains on enabling better cost controls for our communities and increasing flexibility for end-users. In line with our commitment to transparency, we’re sharing our platform and service objectives for the quarter and inviting feedback to ensure our direction reflects what matters most to the communities we serve. See our
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/q2-product-goals/" >product goals from the previous quarter here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The themes below offer a high-level snapshot of where we aim to evolve our offerings in the coming months.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Connect with us&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/u/1/d/1PXGM9_j0nyFLR1FEs7fz9x1vUuhs-J4IvoWGy5r-2aE/edit?fromCopy=true&amp;amp;ct=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Give us feedback&lt;/a> about our direction and how it can improve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://forms.fillout.com/t/uQHVMkgvsuus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Fund parts of this work&lt;/a> if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in making something happen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="demonstrable-reliability-of-our-infrastructure">
Demonstrable reliability of our infrastructure
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#demonstrable-reliability-of-our-infrastructure">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Hub management has many moving parts, and things can go wrong. We want tighter control over the reliability of our infrastructure and better visibility into the status of our community hubs for administrators and members. We will take steps to improve &lt;strong>alerting&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>uptime&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>overall platform reliability&lt;/strong>, as well as review our internal &lt;strong>incident response practices&lt;/strong>. Our goal is to improve the reliability and responsivity of our interactive computing hubs for both administrators and users throughout their community hub lifecycle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="user-level-costs-monitoring-and-group-level-usage-monitoring">
User-level costs monitoring and group-level usage monitoring
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#user-level-costs-monitoring-and-group-level-usage-monitoring">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll build on our recent
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/aws-cost-attribution/" >Grafana dashboard usage monitoring&lt;/a> to add &lt;strong>usage monitoring for user groups&lt;/strong> and begin work on &lt;strong>user-level costs monitoring&lt;/strong>. These are steps toward group-level cost tracking, which will enable better management of team and departmental expenses, especially in large institutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improving-our-incident-response-capability">
Improving our Incident Response capability
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improving-our-incident-response-capability">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As a special-case of doubling down on infrastructure reliability, we&amp;rsquo;re making a concerted effort to improve our incident response processes. This will allow us to respond more reliably and transparently to issues as they arise, and to give our communities confidence about the steps we&amp;rsquo;re taking to resolve them. Our goal is to improve response time and quality, and connect this with infrastructure reliability improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="piloting-a-feature-co-funding-model">
Piloting a feature co-funding model
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#piloting-a-feature-co-funding-model">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This year, 2i2c has experimented with a &lt;strong>collaborative community funding model for platform development&lt;/strong>. This is a way to share funding across communities, and to invite community champions to co-fund projects on the 2i2c roadmap. Our goal is to accelerate upstream development with funded time while minimizing costs for each community. Over the next quarter, we’ll share more details on how the program works, how communities can participate, and what we&amp;rsquo;re learning along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Early candidates for community funding:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Compute quotas&lt;/strong>: Building on our user and group management foundation, we aim to let admins assign compute quotas to users or groups, increasing cost control and easing departmental budgeting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Canvas authentication&lt;/strong>: Integrating with Canvas will enable management of users and groups within Canvas, while using the same data for usage and cost tracking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>nbgitpuller UX improvements&lt;/strong>: Enhance nbgitpuller for sharing interactive projects via a simple link, focusing on error handling, conflict resolution, and per-user authentication for content retrieval.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As we develop this initiative, we’ll need to learn how to credit community partners who co-sponsor work and align our roadmap with the interests of the upstream communities we support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have suggestions for improving this process, or if any features interest your community,
&lt;a href="https://forms.fillout.com/t/uQHVMkgvsuus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >reach out to us&lt;/a> to discuss joining other 2i2c communities in funding and accelerating their development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q4">
Another update coming in Q4
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q4">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Each quarter, we’ll share an update like this to outline our product priorities and track progress. When planning for Q4, we’ll review what we’ve accomplished and provide a community update. Stay tuned!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile,
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/u/1/d/1PXGM9_j0nyFLR1FEs7fz9x1vUuhs-J4IvoWGy5r-2aE/edit?fromCopy=true&amp;amp;ct=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >let us know what you think&lt;/a> about our direction. Your feedback helps us provide the best value to our communities. Thank you!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our strategic and organization-level work is supported by a grant from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> and fees from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/members/" >our member organizations&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Product and team highlights from Q2 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/q2-highlights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/q2-highlights/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post highlights what stood out to us from last quarter and reflects on the
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/q2-product-goals/" >targets we set at the start of the quarter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This quarter, our team learned the importance of shipping iteratively and inviting feedback frequently. In some cases, we learned this the hard way - having spent multiple cycles developing without feedback from community representatives. In other cases, we made rapid progress by working in collaboration with community members in our network. next quarter, we are leaning into this approach as we work towards &lt;strong>building a more standardized and sustainable service&lt;/strong> for our community network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve experienced some disruption and more uncertainty due to the current scientific funding climate, and we&amp;rsquo;re working hard to iterate on this model with feedback from our communities to find a path towards sustainability. We&amp;rsquo;re confident that we&amp;rsquo;ll get there, and improving the value our network of community hubs is a key way to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that in mind, here&amp;rsquo;s what stood out from the quarter:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Find
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupytercon-2025-submissions/" >our JupyterCon 2025 submissions here&lt;/a> to see some other things we&amp;rsquo;re excited about sharing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="group-level-resource-monitoring">
Group-level resource monitoring
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#group-level-resource-monitoring">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Building on our previous work delivering
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/aws-cost-attribution/" >usage monitoring using Prometheus and Grafana&lt;/a>, we&amp;rsquo;ve released
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyterhub-groups-exporter/" >jupyterhub-groups-exporter&lt;/a>, allowing hub administrators to leverage the latest group management features in JupyterHub to monitor group-level resource usage effectively, making it easier to identify usage patterns across teams and departments.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network can learn how to use this in
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/admin/monitoring/grafana-dashboards#getting-a-grafana-account" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our user guide to usage monitoring&lt;/a>. See this
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyterhub-groups-exporter/" >blog post announcing &lt;code>jupyterhub-groups-exporter&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">
Improve creating and sharing custom environments
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Last year we introduced
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyterhub-fancy-profiles-rollout/" >customizable servers via profile lists&lt;/a>. We&amp;rsquo;re building on that - servers can now be configured to
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/user/environment/dynamic-imagebuilding" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >allow users to dynamically specify, build, and share their own custom environment images&lt;/a> without the need for a hub administrator. This will allow community champions with diverse user bases to give their users greater flexibility to support a wide variety of custom computational workflows, accelerating knowledge discovery and sharing. Look out for a blog post on this development in the coming weeks and months.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network can learn how to use this in our &lt;strong>
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/user/environment/dynamic-imagebuilding" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >dynamic image building quick start guide&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="co-located-narrative-content-with-out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">
Co-located narrative content with out-of-the-box Jupyter Book support
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#co-located-narrative-content-with-out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Central to our communities&amp;rsquo; work is sharing new findings, best practices, and community resources. To facilitate that, we&amp;rsquo;ve added support for
&lt;a href="http://next.jupyterbook.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jupyter Book 2&lt;/a> for all of our member communities. Our communities can rapidly build interactive starter documentation and provide users with a rich, interactive, and informative onboarding experience. With a suite of customizable landing-page layouts, colour themes, and component galleries ready to match a community&amp;rsquo;s branding, it&amp;rsquo;s now easier than ever to couple a hub with its own co-located narrative content.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network can learn how to use this in
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/admin/monitoring/cost-users" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our user guide to documentation and sharing&lt;/a>. See
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jb-for-communities/" >this blog post for an announcement&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">
A better onboarding experience for our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We have been working on a streamlined onboarding experience for communities, smoothing out the process of gathering requirements, customizing a hub for the community&amp;rsquo;s specific needs, and delivering new hubs more rapidly. We will be rolling out this process in the next few weeks for new communities onboarding the 2i2c network, and aim to continue learning and refining this process to deliver a faster, smoother onboarding experience for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network will see &lt;strong>changes to our process&lt;/strong> over the coming months that increase the speed and ease of hub delivery.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="efforts-to-improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">
Efforts to improve and formalize the services we deliver to our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#efforts-to-improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As 2i2c has grown over the past few years, it organically developed internal processes for handling common tasks such as the management, rollout and maintenance of hubs, as well as expect consulting to help our communities get the most value out of their hubs. Earlier in the year, we realised it was time to review and refine these processes to better serve our growing community network. As a result of this exercise, we now have tighter service definitions and best practices which clarify what service levels our communities can expect, and how we can internally meet those expectations. We will be publishing our service definitions in the coming months as they are finalized, to ensure full transparency with our communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ You can learn more about our efforts to standardize and scale our services by
&lt;a href="http://2i2c.org/blog" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >following the 2i2c blog&lt;/a>, where we&amp;rsquo;ll share our work as it stabilizes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q3">
Another update coming in Q3
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q3">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll be announcing the focus for our next quarter in a follow-up post, so stay tuned for our next roadmap update, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfo6JFr9L5gEFpk_QjoR23YZ9GHXYaO-3WZWZV3qRz8pj7dbg/viewform?usp=dialog" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >let us know what you think&lt;/a> of our direction - we welcome your feedback!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Thanks to
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> for core support to 2i2c which funds this strategic and organizational work.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>2025-Q1 reflection: Building a foundation for our new platform and membership model</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-reflection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a summary of major progress we made in Q1 of 2025. Its goal is to summarize our major accomplishments and important context before we prioritize for Q2. We hope this gives our community stakeholders a more strategic-level insight into our progress and organizational plans. See
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-product-highlights/" >our Product Highlights for 2025Q1&lt;/a> for a product-focused review. Please
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-reflection/mailto:hello@2i2c.org" >give us feedback&lt;/a> for how we can provide more useful information.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heading into Q1 2025, we had just completed an organizational re-structuring into new functional areas. These were
&lt;a href="https://compass.2i2c.org/product-and-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Products and Services&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://compass.2i2c.org/biz-dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Business Development&lt;/a>, and
&lt;a href="https://compass.2i2c.org/delivery-enablement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Delivery and Team Enablement&lt;/a>. Our
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/funding-navigation/" >support from The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> began in January 2025, and we re-organized around the goals defined in that report. Q1 2025 was the first quarterly cycle under this new system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our primary Q1 2025 goal was to build a solid organizational foundation that will enable us to iterate on our product and business model in Q2. We successfully completed our reorganization into dedicated Business Development and Product teams, and implemented a new quarterly target-setting process across the organization. There are still some key remaining areas to make progress, and we need to ensure that key KPIs and team responsibilities are solidified quickly in Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below we’re sharing a brief update about the major achievements across each area of 2i2c, and first thoughts about outcomes to target in Q2 2025.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="delivery-and-enablement">
Delivery and Enablement
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#delivery-and-enablement">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Goal&lt;/strong>: Develop the operating structure and team skills to efficiently scale our product and service delivery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quarterly Objectives&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>D01&lt;/strong>: Re-organize into product-centric team structure. Define new roles, and accountability practices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>D02&lt;/strong>: Define at least one KPI across each of 2i2c’s areas and complete 2-3 iterations of measurement.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-we-did">
How we did
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#how-we-did">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>We did a good job of taking our first steps at being more structured and intentional about our team and our goals. Our biggest accomplishment was to &lt;strong>significantly improve the Product and Services (P&amp;amp;S) team’s ability to plan and deliver on work&lt;/strong>. We are now measuring velocity as a P&amp;amp;S team, and this gives us a much better understanding of our capacity and a means of optimizing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were slower than expected in defining our new team structures - particularly within the Business Development (BD) team, but I’m confident that we are now on the right track. The biggest remaining challenge is to &lt;strong>refine the relationship between BD and P&amp;amp;S so that we have clear responsibility hand-offs.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have made progress defining KPIs, but have had uneven success in implementing them across the teams. We defined the BD KPIs later than expected, and as a result &lt;strong>we must still operationalize our measurement of those KPIs.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, &lt;strong>we were inconsistent in the way that we completed and documented the work above&lt;/strong>, and did not reliably encode outcomes as a “source of truth” in our team compass. This resulted in some confusion about the status, context, and outcomes of some of the team initiatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="product-and-services">
Product and Services
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#product-and-services">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Goal&lt;/strong>: Create a systematic approach to defining our product value and prioritizing development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quarterly Objectives&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>P01:&lt;/strong> The Product Menu of current capabilities already exists. The focus now should be on finalizing the Product and Services MVP, which is linked to goal S01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>P02:&lt;/strong> Integrate Services into the Product roadmap, prioritizing those needed to enable &lt;strong>S01&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>P03:&lt;/strong> We have designed a qualitative survey to benchmark and record customer satisfaction for any newly released product feature. This survey is already in the process of being sent out to customers of the recent Grafana work, and will be sent out to representative customers of subsequent feature releases.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-we-did-1">
How we did
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#how-we-did-1">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve finalized our product roadmap and incorporated service design priorities into this system as well. It now guides both technical and service development which are the two key ways that we deliver value to our communities. This is a key win for the team, because it means &lt;strong>we can more systematically decide what to build next in order to deliver value to our communities&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also collaborated with the BD team to define our menu of options for communities and ensure they are clearly defined and scalable for our team. This involved a lot of extra back-and-forth that wasn’t planned, but was &lt;strong>critical to ensure we had alignment between our business model and our team’s ability to deliver&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We ran an experiment at conducting community surveys to establish a baseline customer satisfaction KPI and learn if we are building the right things, but didn’t have the response rates that we needed to be useful. &lt;strong>We need to find a way of efficiently creating actionable answers to “are we building the right thing?”&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also agreed on a general principle of measuring community engagement as a primary KPI, but have not yet operationalized it. This is a key metric to &lt;strong>understand whether we’re delivering the value we intend, and whether a community is likely to renew their contract&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, in some cases we have continued to interact with communities in an unscalable way. This is both true for the ways in which we’ve given communities guidance and training, as well as the ways that the P&amp;amp;S team has supported BD in its sales and marketing efforts. It is critical that we &lt;strong>build scalable systems for delivering services to all of our member communities&lt;/strong> to ensure that we deliver value to our entire network of member organizations and not just those we have the strongest connections with. It will also &lt;strong>create more scalable channels of communication and relationship-building with communities&lt;/strong> so that we can support and learn from our entire network.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="business-development">
Business Development
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#business-development">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Goal&lt;/strong>: Create a structured service menu and improve sales tracking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quarterly targets&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>S01&lt;/strong>: Define a tiered pricing and service model&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>S02&lt;/strong>: Define a scalable sales system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>S03&lt;/strong>: Create and operationalize revenue targets and projections&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-we-did-2">
How we did
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#how-we-did-2">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Our BD team built a three-tier membership model that combines monthly fees with active user pricing. &lt;strong>This gives us a foundation to iterate on our pricing and business model.&lt;/strong> Initial anecdotal feedback from renewing communities has been positive, though &lt;strong>we have not yet systematized a process for collecting and incorporating feedback from communities into our sales assets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve completed the first version of our sales CRM to track all customer conversations and tie them to ongoing opportunities. The &lt;strong>CRM is now being used reliably, and has already generated helpful feedback for improvement&lt;/strong>. However &lt;strong>we did not make our intended progress in creating systematized and scalable sales assets&lt;/strong>. It will be critical to build these assets quickly so that we can engage in efficient sales conversations and iterate quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were slower than expected in defining the KPIs that drive BD. We’ve successfully defined the KPIs that should drive BD, but have not operationalized and iterated on business development targets. It will be &lt;strong>critical to measure these BD KPIs and define targets in Q2 in order to set a benchmark of success for BD&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, we were slower than expected in defining the team structure of BD, due to a diffusion of responsibility stemming from our shared leadership model. We’ve clarified that ambiguity and &lt;strong>now have a defined structure of roles and responsibilities within BD&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="concluding-thoughts">
Concluding thoughts
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#concluding-thoughts">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Overall, I consider this quarter a success, given that we are operating with new systems for planning and executing work, as well as a new team structure. We didn&amp;rsquo;t accomplish everything we set out to do in Q1 2025, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s OK for our first quarterly cycle. In Q2 I expect us to be better at scoping the work we aim to accomplish, as well as holding ourselves accountable for getting it done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Q2, we need to prioritize the refinement of our Business Development / Membership model and the system we use for growing and sustaining it. Our P&amp;amp;S team is now much more reliable at planning and delivering work, and our next bottleneck is having a business process that can reliably &lt;em>generate&lt;/em> work and revenue that sustains the organization. This will be a key focus in our Q2 planning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Thanks to
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> for core support to 2i2c which funds this strategic and organizational work.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Our Product and Service goals for Q2 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/q2-product-goals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/q2-product-goals/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>As we head into Q2 of 2025, we continue to focus our work delivering on a small set of core themes that reflect our communities’ most pressing needs. As a part of this process, we want to continue sharing our platform and service goals in an effort to remain transparent, as well as to provide our communities with an opportunity to give us feedback on our direction, and on what’s important for them. See
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-product-goals/" >last quarter’s product goals here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following themes are not guarantees, but should provide a high level view on how we plan to improve our product and services offerings in the next quarter. &lt;strong>If your organization has funding available to support any of the enhancements below,
&lt;a href="https://forms.fillout.com/t/uQHVMkgvsuus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >reach out to us&lt;/a> and we can discuss how you can shape our priorities and outcomes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="give-administrators-more-control">
Give administrators more control
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#give-administrators-more-control">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The implementation of
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/per-user-storage-quota-gcp/" >per-user storage quotas&lt;/a> in Q1 was the start of a set of product initiatives aimed at giving hub administrators more control and peace of mind over unexpected cost overruns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aim to continue giving administrators more control by implementing the ability to &lt;strong>associate users with groups for usage monitoring&lt;/strong>, and as a foundation for future improvements which will deliver &lt;strong>group-level management of storage quotas,&lt;/strong> and later Compute and Dask quotas.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">
Improve creating and sharing custom environments
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>One of the wonderful things about shared open source JupyterHub infrastructure is that it allows community members to share their projects with each other in ways that ensure the work can be fully experienced by the recipient, complete with fully executable content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Q2, we aim to improve the ability for hub users to &lt;strong>build custom environments in their hubs&lt;/strong>, and later to easily &lt;strong>share those custom environments with others&lt;/strong>, ensuring their entire toolchain is replicated in full.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">
Out-of-the-box Jupyter Book support
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We have been working on scoping and building a default JupyterBook implementation
&lt;a href="http://mystmd.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >using the new MyST document engine&lt;/a>, aiming to deliver a default set of tools for &lt;strong>authoring and sharing documentation&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>customizable landing pages&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>interactive training materials&lt;/strong> out of the box with new hub deployments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Q1 we delivered improvements to the JupyterBook launching interface to allow for &lt;strong>automatic hub type detection&lt;/strong>, as well as &lt;strong>landing page components, theming capabilities, galleries and more&lt;/strong>. We aim to complete this work in Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">
A better onboarding experience for our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As more communities in the research and education space join the 2i2c community network, it’s important for us to be ready to deliver the best value we can for them at scale. To that end, we’re &lt;strong>streamlining the processes we use to onboard our communities&lt;/strong>, improving the touchpoints through which we engage with them when they join our community network, and ensuring we create opportunities to better understand their needs in order to set them up for success with their hubs right from the start.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">
Improve and formalize the services we deliver to our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Together with an improved onboarding experience, we aim to improve how we deliver other key services to our communities, including &lt;strong>expert consulting, hub management, and technical support&lt;/strong>, with the aim to offer more scalable, high-value services to address the needs of our communities in a sustainable way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the goals of this service revamp will include improving triaging of support tickets, shortening our issue response time, and providing our community champions with dedicated expertise on subjects including open source science and tools, community participation in open science, fundraising and grantsmanship co-creation, engineering consultancy and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q3">
Another update coming in Q3
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q3">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We’ll use this blog post as an informal roadmap of our product goals for the quarter, striving to advance as many of the outlined areas as possible. During our Q3 planning, we’ll reflect on the achievements made in line with this initiative and share a progress update with our community. Keep an eye out for more details!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our strategic and organization-level work is supported by a grant from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> and fees from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/members/" >our member organizations&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Our product highlights from Q2 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-product-highlights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-product-highlights/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>These describe the major service improvements that we rolled out in Q1 2025. See this
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/q1-product-goals/" >blog post describing our product enhancement goals in Q1 2025&lt;/a> for the targets we intended to hit this quarter. Below is a brief description of what we accomplished.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="user-storage-quotas">
User storage quotas
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#user-storage-quotas">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A key part of 2i2c’s service is &lt;strong>making the cloud safe to try&lt;/strong>. One of the biggest concerns from our communities is that their cloud costs will be unexpectedly high. This quarter we decided to make cloud storage a bit safer. Storage can get expensive, especially when a user accidentally downloads a particularly large file - they may not even realize that doing so incurs an extra cost. For this reason, we added the ability to limit user storage on JupyterHubs:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/per-user-storage-quota/" >Enforcing per-user storage quotas with &lt;code>jupyterhub-home-nfs&lt;/code>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We initially deployed this feature on our AWS hubs, and followed up by deploying it on GCP hubs as well. Any community with a hub on AWS and GCP now has the ability to limit the storage that their users receive, greatly increasing our communities’ control over their costs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/per-user-storage-quota-gcp/" >Enforcing per-user storage quotas now available on GCP&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Thanks to&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="https://developmentseed.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >DevSeed&lt;/a> for collaboration on this work, in addition to the
&lt;a href="https://www.earthdata.nasa.gov/data/tools/veda" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >NASA VEDA project&lt;/a> for funding this effort.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="automated-backups-for-gcp-hubs">
Automated backups for GCP hubs
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#automated-backups-for-gcp-hubs">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Another concern communities have is “what happens if something breaks and I lose data?” Cloud providers offer a number of ways to recover from disasters like this, and we did some work enabling this for GCP so that communities have disaster recovery options available to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/gcp-filestore-backups/" >Announcing backups for GCP-hosted hubs!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deploying-jupyterhub-on-public-infrastructure">
Deploying JupyterHub on public infrastructure
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#deploying-jupyterhub-on-public-infrastructure">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Deploying Kubernetes and JupyterHub on publicly-managed infrastructure could be an excellent way to reduce the perceived risk of depending on large tech companies for their key workflows, and potentially reduce costs by using federal infrastructure that can be paid with special grant funding. We built team expertise in deploying and running JupyterHub and BinderHub on JetStream2, and have promising results that we hope to build upon in Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jetstream-binderhub/" >Open infrastructure for collaborative geoscience with Project Pythia: Learning how to deploy a BinderHub on Jetstream2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Thanks to&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="https://jetstream-cloud.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jetstream2&lt;/a> for an ACCESS allocation, to Julian Pistorius for technical support, to
&lt;a href="https://projectpythia.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Project Pythia&lt;/a> (NSF award 2324302) for funding this work, and to
&lt;a href="https://www.zonca.dev/posts/2024-12-11-jetstream_kubernetes_magnum" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Andrea Zonca&lt;/a> for preliminary work on Kubernetes deployments on Jetstream 2.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="upgrading-to-the-latest-jupyterhub-version">
Upgrading to the latest JupyterHub version
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#upgrading-to-the-latest-jupyterhub-version">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We upgraded all of 2i2c’s community hubs to use JupyterHub 5.0. This brings in a bunch of security improvements, bugfixes, and enhancements. You can find links to the highlights and changelog in our blog post below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyterhub5-upgrade/" >2i2c hubs now run JupyterHub 5.0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reproducible-environments-for-community-members">
Reproducible environments for community members
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#reproducible-environments-for-community-members">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Finally, we did a bit of product brainstorming around enabling communities to bring their environments with them when they publish. We are interested in making it easy to re-use a community’s hub infrastructure to provide the reproducible environments needed for publishing or communicating their work externally. Here’s a brief brainstorm for what this could look like:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/frictionless-reproducibility/" >Towards frictionless, portable, and sustainable reproducibility with Binder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improving-the-ux-and-flexibility-of-community-documentation-with-myst">
Improving the UX and flexibility of community documentation with MyST
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improving-the-ux-and-flexibility-of-community-documentation-with-myst">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>To provide our communities with quality documentation that sits alongside their Hubs, we have been working on improving MyST to allow for a more flexible and usable document authoring experience, with improvements to landing page layouts, theming, galleries, button layouts, and project launching. We’re aiming to deliver a complete MVP covering our communities’ most requested features by the end of Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-case-you-missed-it">
In case you missed it
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#in-case-you-missed-it">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Finally, below are a few other blog posts where we’ve documented major impact stories and organizational updates:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Community impact&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/hackweek-shoutout/" >Harnessing Marine Open Data Science for Ocean Sustainability in Africa, South Asia and Latin America&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/veda-update-q4-2024/" >NASA VEDA &amp;amp; 2i2c Update for Q4 2024 (Oct-Dec 2024)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Open Source impact&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyter-executive-council/" >Chris is joining Project Jupyter&amp;rsquo;s Executive Council&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://blog.jupyter.org/simplifying-and-speeding-up-binder-builds-with-buildkit-d44f96582994" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Simplifying and speeding up Binder builds with BuildKit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/binder-singlenode/" >2i2c joins the mybinder.org federation with a cheaper and faster way to deploy Binderhub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/jupyter-book-cors/" >Designing for an ecosystem: a case study in cross-project open source contribution&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Organizational updates&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/community-ownership/" >Announcing our formal commitment to open technology&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our strategic and organization-level work is supported by a grant from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> and fees from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/members/" >our member organizations&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>