<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Georgiana Dolocan | 2i2c</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/georgiana-dolocan/</link><atom:link href="https://2i2c.org/author/georgiana-dolocan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Georgiana Dolocan</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://2i2c.org/author/georgiana-dolocan/avatar_hu5a78bf28ffb183ff0de0c23a9805fa26_292451_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Georgiana Dolocan</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/georgiana-dolocan/</link></image><item><title>Georgiana Dolocan</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/georgiana-dolocan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/author/georgiana-dolocan/</guid><description>&lt;p>Software Engineer irreversibly in love with open source. A JupyterHub team member, focusing on infrastructure and community growth. Previously JupyterHub Contributor in Residence and Outreachy intern through an internship that supports diversity in open source and free software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open infrastructure for collaborative geoscience with Project Pythia: Learning how to deploy a BinderHub on Jetstream2</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jetstream-binderhub/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jetstream-binderhub/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="project-pythia-and-the-jupyter-notebook-obsolescence-problem">
Project Pythia and the &amp;ldquo;Jupyter notebook obsolescence&amp;rdquo; problem
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#project-pythia-and-the-jupyter-notebook-obsolescence-problem">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://projectpythia.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Project Pythia&lt;/a> provides educational resources for essential software tools that enable open, reproducible and scalable geoscience, such as the
&lt;a href="https://pangeo.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Pangeo&lt;/a> stack of packages (Xarray, Dask, Jupyter). Their &lt;em>Cookbooks&lt;/em> are crowdsourced, community-curated, and open-source collections of Jupyter notebooks that demonstrate how to use these tools for cloud-native, geoscientific workflows (see our
&lt;a href="" >Project Pythia Cookoff&lt;/a> blog post). However, &amp;ldquo;Jupyter notebook obsolescence&amp;rdquo; is a common problem: tutorials that were created a few years ago may no longer work due to changes in the software ecosystem and hampers the reproducibility of scientific results. A reproducible execution environment and the infrastructure to support it are essential for the long-term sustainability of these educational resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="leveraging-nsf-funded-cyberinfrastructure-for-binderhub">
Leveraging NSF-funded cyberinfrastructure for BinderHub
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#leveraging-nsf-funded-cyberinfrastructure-for-binderhub">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A
&lt;a href="https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >BinderHub&lt;/a> allows users to dynamically create custom computing environments from
&lt;a href="https://mybinder.readthedocs.io/en/latest/introduction.html#what-is-a-binder" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Binder-ready&lt;/a> repositories containing computational notebooks and configuration files that describe the software environment required to run them. A public Binder service exists at
&lt;a href="https://mybinder.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >mybinder.org&lt;/a> (see our blog post about
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/binder-singlenode/" >joining the mybinder federation&lt;/a> 🎉) and is a successful example of how open cloud infrastructure can accommodate reproducible execution environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resources available on such a public service are limited therefore 2i2c, together with Project Pythia, have been exploring how to deploy a BinderHub backed by larger resources from the NSF-funded cloud computing platform
&lt;a href="https://jetstream-cloud.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jetstream2&lt;/a>. This allows for larger simultaneous user loads, such as at workshops, as well as access to more powerful distributed and parallelized workflows required to process large geoscientific datasets, under a persistent resource allocation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learning-how-to-deploy-on-openstack">
Learning how to deploy on OpenStack
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#learning-how-to-deploy-on-openstack">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Jetstream2 uses
&lt;a href="https://www.openstack.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >OpenStack&lt;/a> in order to manage pools of compute, storage and networking resources, and for our purposes we specifically make use of OpenStack
&lt;a href="https://docs.openstack.org/magnum/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Magnum&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://specs.openstack.org/openstack//magnum-specs/specs/bobcat/clusterapi-driver.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Cluster API driver&lt;/a> to manage Kubernetes for our deployment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cluster API needs a &lt;code>CAPI management cluster&lt;/code> in order to manage other Kubernetes clusters, called workload clusters. On Jetstream2, this management cluster is gracefully created and operated by the Jetstream2 team, which means that the only task to worry about is creating and configuring the workload cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the workload cluster we used the
&lt;a href="https://registry.terraform.io/providers/terraform-provider-openstack/openstack/latest/docs" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Openstack Terraform provider&lt;/a> to define the cluster template, the cluster itself and the node groups in a reproducible way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the cluster infrastructure was successfully created on Jetstream2, thanks to the 2i2c hub infrastructure being cloud agnostic as well, deploying BinderHub to Jetstream2, was a seamless experience and it was no different than on other cloud providers that we already supported.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also learnt about some limitations of the Openstack Magnum driver project, which were expected given it being a relatively recent project, slowly being adopted, but they were all reported upstream and hopefully will soon be fixed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://jetstream-cloud.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jetstream2&lt;/a>: Explore ACCESS allocation and Julian Pistorius for technical support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://projectpythia.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Project Pythia&lt;/a> (NSF award 2324302)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://www.zonca.dev/posts/2024-12-11-jetstream_kubernetes_magnum" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Andrea Zonca&lt;/a> for preliminary work on Kubernetes deployments on Jetstream 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>2i2c hubs now run JupyterHub 5.0</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyterhub5-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyterhub5-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are excited to announce that all 2i2c hubs now run JupyterHub 5.0!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is an upgrade that brings some exciting new features and improvements. Some of the highlights include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The possibility to enable
&lt;a href="https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/5.0.0/tutorial/sharing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >user-initiated server sharing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/5.0.0/reference/authenticators.html#authenticator-managed-roles" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Authenticator-managed roles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Also, JupyterHub 5 will enable us to offer per-group shared directories in the future!
&lt;a href="https://github.com/NASA-IMPACT/veda-jupyterhub/issues/61" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Tracking Issue&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Checkout the
&lt;a href="https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/howto/upgrading-v5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >JupyterHub 5.0 migration&lt;/a> docs or the
&lt;a href="https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/5.0.0/reference/changelog.html#id3" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >changelog&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the Jupyter Blog: From intern to mentor.</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2023/external-jupyter-georgiana-mentor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2023/external-jupyter-georgiana-mentor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CILogon usage at 2i2c</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2023/cilogon-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2023/cilogon-integration/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="about-cilogon">
About CILogon
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#about-cilogon">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://www.cilogon.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >CILogon&lt;/a> is an open source service provider that allows users to log in against over 4000 various identity providers, including campus identity providers. The available identity providers are members of
&lt;a href="https://incommon.org/federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >InCommon&lt;/a>, a federation of universities and other organizations that provide single sign-on access to various resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cilogon-and-2i2c">
CILogon and 2i2c
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#cilogon-and-2i2c">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>For the past year, 2i2c has been successfully using CILogon for more than fifteen of the hubs it manages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, most of the hubs that use it are hubs for communities in education that want to manage their hub access through their own institutional providers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With using a tool like CILogon, we allow hub access to be managed both through the communities&amp;rsquo; institutional providers, but also through social providers like GitHub and Google. Because both authentication mechanisms can coexist, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to provide specific credentials for 2i2c staff in order to have access to the hub. This reduces both the burden on institution&amp;rsquo;s IT departments, but also the complexity of a hub deployment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreover, as we migrate away from our current Auth0 setup, the number of hubs using CILogon will further increase in the following year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-setup">
The setup
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#the-setup">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The setup that 2i2c uses, is based on two important tools, the CILogon administrative client and the JupyterHub CILogonOAuthenticator.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-cilogon-administrative-client">
The CILogon administrative client
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#the-cilogon-administrative-client">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The
&lt;a href="https://cilogon.github.io/oa4mp/server/manuals/dynamic-client-registration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >2i2c administrative client&lt;/a> provided by CILogon allowed us to automatically manage the CILogon OAuth applications needed for authenticating into the hub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For each hub that uses CILogon, we dynamically create an OAuth
&lt;a href="https://cilogon.github.io/oa4mp/server/manuals/dynamic-client-registration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >client application&lt;/a> in CILogon and store the credentials safely, using the script at
&lt;a href="https://github.com/2i2c-org/infrastructure/blob/3312f373f0aa59fbc98dc1c8161aa9623b68726b/deployer/cilogon_app.py" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >cilogon_app.py&lt;/a>. The script can also used for &lt;code>updating&lt;/code> the callback URLs of an existing OAuth application, &lt;code>deleting&lt;/code> a CILogon OAuth application when a hub is removed or changes authentication methods, &lt;code>getting&lt;/code> details about an existing OAuth application, &lt;code>getting all&lt;/code> existing 2i2c CILogon OAuth applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-jupyterhub-cilogonoauthenticator">
The JupyterHub CILogonOAuthenticator
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#the-jupyterhub-cilogonoauthenticator">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>For CILogon&amp;rsquo;s integration with JupyterHub&amp;rsquo;s authentication workflow, we&amp;rsquo;re using the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyterhub/oauthenticator/blob/main/oauthenticator/cilogon.py" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >&lt;strong>CILogonOAuthenticator&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, which is part of the
&lt;a href="https://oauthenticator.readthedocs.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >JupyterHub OAuthenticator project&lt;/a>. This is what allows JupyterHub to use common OAuth providers for authentication, and it&amp;rsquo;s also a base for writing other Authenticators with any OAuth 2.0 provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of this 2i2c integration with the JupyterHub CILogonOAuthenticator some important upstream fixes and enhancements to the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyterhub/oauthenticator" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >&lt;code>oauthenticator&lt;/code>&lt;/a> were identified and performed. For example, the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyterhub/oauthenticator/security/advisories/GHSA-r7v4-jwx9-wx43" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >GHSA-r7v4-jwx9-wx43&lt;/a> vulnerability was reported and fixed, and a
&lt;a href="https://oauthenticator.readthedocs.io/en/latest/how-to/migrations/upgrade-to-15.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >migration guide&lt;/a> containing a description of the breaking changes that were made, together with a step by step guide for the users on how to update their usage of JupyterHub CILogonOAuthenticator was provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read more about how CILogon is setup for use at 2i2c from
&lt;a href="https://infrastructure.2i2c.org/hub-deployment-guide/configure-auth/cilogon.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >the docs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="celebration">
Celebration
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#celebration">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Thanks to the 2i2c - CILogon partnership, during this past year we were able to integrate CILogon into 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure and to observe its importance, usefulness and great support for 2i2c and the communities we server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are now happy to announce that the 2i2c - CILogon partnership has been expanded to another year!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Acknowledgements&lt;/strong>: The upstream
&lt;a href="https://oauthenticator.readthedocs.io/en/latest" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >&lt;code>jupyterhub-oauthenticator&lt;/code>&lt;/a> project mentioned in this post as being used at 2i2c is a JupyterHub package, kindly developed and maintained by the
&lt;a href="https://discourse.jupyter.org/c/jupyterhub/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >JupyterHub community&lt;/a> and the 2i2c integration described was developed by
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/organization/" >the 2i2c engineering team&lt;/a>. Also, this post was edited by
&lt;a href="https://jbasney.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jim Basney&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>