<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Giuliano Maccioci | 2i2c</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maccioci/</link><atom:link href="https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maccioci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Giuliano Maccioci</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://2i2c.org/media/sharing.png</url><title>Giuliano Maccioci</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maccioci/</link></image><item><title>Our product highlights from Q2 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q1-product-highlights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q1-product-highlights/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>These describe the major service improvements that we rolled out in Q1 2025. See this
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q1-product-goals/" >blog post describing our product enhancement goals in Q1 2025&lt;/a> for the targets we intended to hit this quarter. Below is a brief description of what we accomplished.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="user-storage-quotas">
User storage quotas
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#user-storage-quotas">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A key part of 2i2c’s service is &lt;strong>making the cloud safe to try&lt;/strong>. One of the biggest concerns from our communities is that their cloud costs will be unexpectedly high. This quarter we decided to make cloud storage a bit safer. Storage can get expensive, especially when a user accidentally downloads a particularly large file - they may not even realize that doing so incurs an extra cost. For this reason, we added the ability to limit user storage on JupyterHubs:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/per-user-storage-quota/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Enforcing per-user storage quotas with &lt;code>jupyterhub-home-nfs&lt;/code>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We initially deployed this feature on our AWS hubs, and followed up by deploying it on GCP hubs as well. Any community with a hub on AWS and GCP now has the ability to limit the storage that their users receive, greatly increasing our communities’ control over their costs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/per-user-storage-quota-gcp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Enforcing per-user storage quotas now available on GCP&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Thanks to&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="https://developmentseed.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >DevSeed&lt;/a> for collaboration on this work, in addition to the
&lt;a href="https://www.earthdata.nasa.gov/data/tools/veda" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >NASA VEDA project&lt;/a> for funding this effort.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="automated-backups-for-gcp-hubs">
Automated backups for GCP hubs
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#automated-backups-for-gcp-hubs">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Another concern communities have is “what happens if something breaks and I lose data?” Cloud providers offer a number of ways to recover from disasters like this, and we did some work enabling this for GCP so that communities have disaster recovery options available to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/gcp-filestore-backups/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Announcing backups for GCP-hosted hubs!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deploying-jupyterhub-on-public-infrastructure">
Deploying JupyterHub on public infrastructure
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#deploying-jupyterhub-on-public-infrastructure">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Deploying Kubernetes and JupyterHub on publicly-managed infrastructure could be an excellent way to reduce the perceived risk of depending on large tech companies for their key workflows, and potentially reduce costs by using federal infrastructure that can be paid with special grant funding. We built team expertise in deploying and running JupyterHub and BinderHub on JetStream2, and have promising results that we hope to build upon in Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jetstream-binderhub/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Open infrastructure for collaborative geoscience with Project Pythia: Learning how to deploy a BinderHub on Jetstream2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Thanks to&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="https://jetstream-cloud.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jetstream2&lt;/a> for an ACCESS allocation, to Julian Pistorius for technical support, to
&lt;a href="https://projectpythia.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Project Pythia&lt;/a> (NSF award 2324302) for funding this work, and to
&lt;a href="https://www.zonca.dev/posts/2024-12-11-jetstream_kubernetes_magnum" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Andrea Zonca&lt;/a> for preliminary work on Kubernetes deployments on Jetstream 2.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="upgrading-to-the-latest-jupyterhub-version">
Upgrading to the latest JupyterHub version
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#upgrading-to-the-latest-jupyterhub-version">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We upgraded all of 2i2c’s community hubs to use JupyterHub 5.0. This brings in a bunch of security improvements, bugfixes, and enhancements. You can find links to the highlights and changelog in our blog post below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyterhub5-upgrade/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >2i2c hubs now run JupyterHub 5.0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reproducible-environments-for-community-members">
Reproducible environments for community members
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#reproducible-environments-for-community-members">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Finally, we did a bit of product brainstorming around enabling communities to bring their environments with them when they publish. We are interested in making it easy to re-use a community’s hub infrastructure to provide the reproducible environments needed for publishing or communicating their work externally. Here’s a brief brainstorm for what this could look like:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/frictionless-reproducibility/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Towards frictionless, portable, and sustainable reproducibility with Binder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improving-the-ux-and-flexibility-of-community-documentation-with-myst">
Improving the UX and flexibility of community documentation with MyST
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improving-the-ux-and-flexibility-of-community-documentation-with-myst">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>To provide our communities with quality documentation that sits alongside their Hubs, we have been working on improving MyST to allow for a more flexible and usable document authoring experience, with improvements to landing page layouts, theming, galleries, button layouts, and project launching. We’re aiming to deliver a complete MVP covering our communities’ most requested features by the end of Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-case-you-missed-it">
In case you missed it
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#in-case-you-missed-it">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Finally, below are a few other blog posts where we’ve documented major impact stories and organizational updates:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Community impact&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/hackweek-shoutout/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Harnessing Marine Open Data Science for Ocean Sustainability in Africa, South Asia and Latin America&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/veda-update-q4-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >NASA VEDA &amp;amp; 2i2c Update for Q4 2024 (Oct-Dec 2024)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Open Source impact&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyter-executive-council/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Chris is joining Project Jupyter&amp;rsquo;s Executive Council&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://blog.jupyter.org/simplifying-and-speeding-up-binder-builds-with-buildkit-d44f96582994" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Simplifying and speeding up Binder builds with BuildKit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/binder-singlenode/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >2i2c joins the mybinder.org federation with a cheaper and faster way to deploy Binderhub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyter-book-cors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Designing for an ecosystem: a case study in cross-project open source contribution&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Organizational updates&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/community-ownership/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Announcing our formal commitment to open technology&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Our product goals for Q1 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q1-product-goals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q1-product-goals/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This quarterly post is coming out a little bit late - our goal was to post this in early January, but the year has been more complicated than we bargained for :-)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past year, 2i2c has made team-wide efforts to improve our product planning and delivery. A key part of this is re-organizing an integrated
&lt;a href="https://compass.2i2c.org/product-and-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Product and Services team&lt;/a> that brings our strategic planning, engineering, and service delivery closer together. We&amp;rsquo;ve also built systems for planning and measuring progress within the P&amp;amp;S team, and a product initiatives system for planning major work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our goal is to &lt;strong>organize our product work around a small set of core themes&lt;/strong> to help us focus and prioritize. As part of this, we’d like to share platform enhancement goals for roughly each quarter. These are not guarantees, but we share them to be transparent about where we think we can be the most impactful in the next few months. Here are the major areas we hope to improve 2i2c’ platform in Q1 2025.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="expand-access-to-cloud-providers-and-improve-data-safety">
Expand access to cloud providers and improve data safety
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#expand-access-to-cloud-providers-and-improve-data-safety">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>One of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s goals is to showcase the ability of open infrastructure to be deployed on a variety of infrastructure proiders. This includes user-facing features, as well as guardrails and safety measures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we are working to bring closer feature parity between hub deployments on AWS and GCP, while enabling disaster recovery with automated home directory backups.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explore-deploying-on-public-infrastructure-providers">
Explore deploying on public infrastructure providers
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#explore-deploying-on-public-infrastructure-providers">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Many communities in research and education are interested in leveraging publicly-owned infrastructure providers like
&lt;a href="https://jetstream-cloud.org/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >JetStream 2&lt;/a> and the
&lt;a href="https://nationalresearchplatform.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >National Research Platform&lt;/a>. While 2i2c has historically focused on commercial cloud due to their highly-reliable Kubernetes platforms, we think it is important to explore publicly-owned infrastructure providers as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we&amp;rsquo;ll begin this expansion by deploying JupyterHubs and BinderHubs on JetStream 2, which will give communities access to publicly-funded computing resources. We will use this experience to decide whether it&amp;rsquo;s sustainable for us to deploy on this and other publicly-owned infrastructure providers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enable-enhanced-community-knowledge-bases-with-jupyter-book-2">
Enable enhanced community knowledge bases with Jupyter Book 2
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#enable-enhanced-community-knowledge-bases-with-jupyter-book-2">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A key theme we aim to enable is &lt;strong>sharing&lt;/strong> within and between community hubs. This is a critical part of the data science workflow because it allows people to collaborate on the same ideas, and build on top of one another&amp;rsquo;s ideas. An early target for this is to facilitate lightweight sharing of computational content so that community members can learn from one another more effectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we want to help get
&lt;a href="https://next.jupyterbook.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jupyter Book 2&amp;rsquo;s beta&lt;/a> released, and provide an out-of-the-box configuration for our communities to use it with their hubs. This includes adding landing pages and better integration with JupyterHub via launch buttons to create a more seamless experience between documentation and interactive computing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enable-sharing-reproducible-environments-on-a-hub">
Enable sharing reproducible environments on a hub
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#enable-sharing-reproducible-environments-on-a-hub">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Another key aspect of sharing is &lt;strong>sharing the computational environment as well&lt;/strong>. This would allow communities to not only sheir their content, but also live infrastructure that allows others to reproduce and interact with their work. We think that investing more time into imiproving and deploying
&lt;a href="https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >BinderHubs&lt;/a> (the technology behind
&lt;a href="https://mybinder.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >mybinder.org&lt;/a>) will help us learn more about how to make this a reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we plan to grow our capacity to deploy BinderHubs across multiple cloud providers. This will allow hub users to build their own Binder environments on the fly and make it possible to share these environments with others, enabling better reproducibility and collaboration within communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="give-communities-more-visibility-and-control-over-their-hub-setup-and-costs">
Give communities more visibility and control over their hub setup and costs
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#give-communities-more-visibility-and-control-over-their-hub-setup-and-costs">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Perhaps the biggest perceived risk to using cloud infrastructure is the possibility of &lt;strong>runaway costs&lt;/strong>. Community leaders are often nervous that something unexpected will happen and they&amp;rsquo;ll have to foot a giant bill at the end of the month. We think that reducing this risk is a key way to make cloud infrastructure safer and more useful for research and education communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we are aim to add more &lt;strong>visibility into hub usage&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>more controls over resources via quotas&lt;/strong>. This will allow more fine control over resource budgets such as CPU, memory, and storage. We&amp;rsquo;ll also work on &lt;strong>assigning users to groups&lt;/strong>, allowing communities greater control over resource allocation across large user bases.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="standardize-our-hub-service-menu-of-options-and-prices">
Standardize our hub service menu of options and prices
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#standardize-our-hub-service-menu-of-options-and-prices">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A key goal of our
&lt;a href="" >Navigation Fund grant&lt;/a> is to streamline ourselves into a few repeatable, scalable service offerings at different price points. This will allow us to more easily support new communities and provide a more consistent experience for users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we&amp;rsquo;d like to define a starting point that we can begin to iterate on. We&amp;rsquo;ll define a new set of pricing based around a tiered service model, and decide on an initial set of features and services to include with each. Our goal will be to have something defined quickly so that we can iterate a few times with community feedback before the quarter is over.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="standardize-our-community-support-services">
Standardize our community support services
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#standardize-our-community-support-services">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ve audited our ongoing support practices and realized that we aren&amp;rsquo;t always delivering them in an efficient way. We often share the same information one-on-one conversations, and aren&amp;rsquo;t effectively leveraging our community network to support and learn from one another. We&amp;rsquo;d like to standardize and boost the scalability of our support services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In Q1 2025&lt;/strong> we want to explore how we can more scalably and efficiently provide hands-on guidance, expert co-creation, and support to communities. Our goal is to define a starting point for these services so that we can offer this support in a sustainable way and begin to learn from our experiences. We also want to build a mechanism for scoping (and pricing) additional capacity that is needed beyond standard community services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q2">
Another update coming in Q2
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q2">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Our aim is to use this blog post as a guide for the quarter, and to make progress in as many areas above as we can. As part of our Q2 planning process, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide a retrospective on the accomplishments we&amp;rsquo;ve made towards this effort, and will provide an update for our community on our progress. Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>