<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Giuliano Maciocci | 2i2c</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maciocci/</link><atom:link href="https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maciocci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Giuliano Maciocci</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maciocci/avatar_hub476b85606dbed83ed86b6f1164e1fdb_3350_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Giuliano Maciocci</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maciocci/</link></image><item><title>Giuliano Maciocci</title><link>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maciocci/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/author/giuliano-maciocci/</guid><description>&lt;p>Giuliano is a product specialist with an extensive User Experience background and strong analytical skills, I help organisations define their product development roadmaps and customer engagement strategies with a user-focused, data-driven approach that starts by building a shared understanding of what constitutes value, then structures and empowers the organisational talent needed to deliver it. (from Giuliano&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gmaciocci/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >LinkedIn profile&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>10+ years experience driving growth in companies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ex-Chief Product Officer at Ex Ordo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ex-head of Product at eLife Sciences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led the open science product Executable Research Article&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led Qualcomm to $65M platform sale&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contributed significantly to mobile design and innovation at Adobe.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Our Product and Service goals for Q3 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q3-goals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q3-goals/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we enter Q3 2025, our focus remains on enabling better cost controls for our communities and increasing flexibility for end-users. In line with our commitment to transparency, we’re sharing our platform and service objectives for the quarter and inviting feedback to ensure our direction reflects what matters most to the communities we serve. See our
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q2-product-goals/" >product goals from the previous quarter here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The themes below offer a high-level snapshot of where we aim to evolve our offerings in the coming months.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Connect with us&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/u/1/d/1PXGM9_j0nyFLR1FEs7fz9x1vUuhs-J4IvoWGy5r-2aE/edit?fromCopy=true&amp;amp;ct=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Give us feedback&lt;/a> about our direction and how it can improve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://forms.fillout.com/t/uQHVMkgvsuus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Fund parts of this work&lt;/a> if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in making something happen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="demonstrable-reliability-of-our-infrastructure">
Demonstrable reliability of our infrastructure
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#demonstrable-reliability-of-our-infrastructure">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Hub management has many moving parts, and things can go wrong. We want tighter control over the reliability of our infrastructure and better visibility into the status of our community hubs for administrators and members. We will take steps to improve &lt;strong>alerting&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>uptime&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>overall platform reliability&lt;/strong>, as well as review our internal &lt;strong>incident response practices&lt;/strong>. Our goal is to improve the reliability and responsivity of our interactive computing hubs for both administrators and users throughout their community hub lifecycle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="user-level-costs-monitoring-and-group-level-usage-monitoring">
User-level costs monitoring and group-level usage monitoring
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#user-level-costs-monitoring-and-group-level-usage-monitoring">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll build on our recent
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/aws-cost-attribution/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Grafana dashboard usage monitoring&lt;/a> to add &lt;strong>usage monitoring for user groups&lt;/strong> and begin work on &lt;strong>user-level costs monitoring&lt;/strong>. These are steps toward group-level cost tracking, which will enable better management of team and departmental expenses, especially in large institutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improving-our-incident-response-capability">
Improving our Incident Response capability
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improving-our-incident-response-capability">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As a special-case of doubling down on infrastructure reliability, we&amp;rsquo;re making a concerted effort to improve our incident response processes. This will allow us to respond more reliably and transparently to issues as they arise, and to give our communities confidence about the steps we&amp;rsquo;re taking to resolve them. Our goal is to improve response time and quality, and connect this with infrastructure reliability improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="piloting-a-feature-co-funding-model">
Piloting a feature co-funding model
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#piloting-a-feature-co-funding-model">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This year, 2i2c has experimented with a &lt;strong>collaborative community funding model for platform development&lt;/strong>. This is a way to share funding across communities, and to invite community champions to co-fund projects on the 2i2c roadmap. Our goal is to accelerate upstream development with funded time while minimizing costs for each community. Over the next quarter, we’ll share more details on how the program works, how communities can participate, and what we&amp;rsquo;re learning along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Early candidates for community funding:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Compute quotas&lt;/strong>: Building on our user and group management foundation, we aim to let admins assign compute quotas to users or groups, increasing cost control and easing departmental budgeting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Canvas authentication&lt;/strong>: Integrating with Canvas will enable management of users and groups within Canvas, while using the same data for usage and cost tracking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>nbgitpuller UX improvements&lt;/strong>: Enhance nbgitpuller for sharing interactive projects via a simple link, focusing on error handling, conflict resolution, and per-user authentication for content retrieval.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As we develop this initiative, we’ll need to learn how to credit community partners who co-sponsor work and align our roadmap with the interests of the upstream communities we support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have suggestions for improving this process, or if any features interest your community,
&lt;a href="https://forms.fillout.com/t/uQHVMkgvsuus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >reach out to us&lt;/a> to discuss joining other 2i2c communities in funding and accelerating their development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q4">
Another update coming in Q4
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q4">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Each quarter, we’ll share an update like this to outline our product priorities and track progress. When planning for Q4, we’ll review what we’ve accomplished and provide a community update. Stay tuned!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile,
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/u/1/d/1PXGM9_j0nyFLR1FEs7fz9x1vUuhs-J4IvoWGy5r-2aE/edit?fromCopy=true&amp;amp;ct=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >let us know what you think&lt;/a> about our direction. Your feedback helps us provide the best value to our communities. Thank you!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our strategic and organization-level work is supported by a grant from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> and fees from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/members/" >our member organizations&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Product and team highlights from Q2 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q2-highlights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q2-highlights/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post highlights what stood out to us from last quarter and reflects on the
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q2-product-goals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >targets we set at the start of the quarter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This quarter, our team learned the importance of shipping iteratively and inviting feedback frequently. In some cases, we learned this the hard way - having spent multiple cycles developing without feedback from community representatives. In other cases, we made rapid progress by working in collaboration with community members in our network. next quarter, we are leaning into this approach as we work towards &lt;strong>building a more standardized and sustainable service&lt;/strong> for our community network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve experienced some disruption and more uncertainty due to the current scientific funding climate, and we&amp;rsquo;re working hard to iterate on this model with feedback from our communities to find a path towards sustainability. We&amp;rsquo;re confident that we&amp;rsquo;ll get there, and improving the value our network of community hubs is a key way to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that in mind, here&amp;rsquo;s what stood out from the quarter:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Find
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupytercon-2025-submissions/" >our JupyterCon 2025 submissions here&lt;/a> to see some other things we&amp;rsquo;re excited about sharing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="group-level-resource-monitoring">
Group-level resource monitoring
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#group-level-resource-monitoring">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Building on our previous work delivering
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/aws-cost-attribution/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >usage monitoring using Prometheus and Grafana&lt;/a>, we&amp;rsquo;ve released
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyterhub-groups-exporter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >jupyterhub-groups-exporter&lt;/a>, allowing hub administrators to leverage the latest group management features in JupyterHub to monitor group-level resource usage effectively, making it easier to identify usage patterns across teams and departments.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network can learn how to use this in
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/admin/howto/monitoring/grafana-dashboards/#getting-a-grafana-account" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our user guide to usage monitoring&lt;/a>. See this
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jupyterhub-groups-exporter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >blog post announcing &lt;code>jupyterhub-groups-exporter&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">
Improve creating and sharing custom environments
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Last year we introduced
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2024/jupyterhub-fancy-profiles-rollout/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >customizable servers via profile lists&lt;/a>. We&amp;rsquo;re building on that - servers can now be configured to
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/user/topics/dynamic-imagebuilding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >allow users to dynamically specify, build, and share their own custom environment images&lt;/a> without the need for a hub administrator. This will allow community champions with diverse user bases to give their users greater flexibility to support a wide variety of custom computational workflows, accelerating knowledge discovery and sharing. Look out for a blog post on this development in the coming weeks and months.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network can learn how to use this in our &lt;strong>
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/user/topics/dynamic-imagebuilding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >dynamic image building quick start guide&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="co-located-narrative-content-with-out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">
Co-located narrative content with out-of-the-box Jupyter Book support
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#co-located-narrative-content-with-out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Central to our communities&amp;rsquo; work is sharing new findings, best practices, and community resources. To facilitate that, we&amp;rsquo;ve added support for
&lt;a href="http://next.jupyterbook.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Jupyter Book 2&lt;/a> for all of our member communities. Our communities can rapidly build interactive starter documentation and provide users with a rich, interactive, and informative onboarding experience. With a suite of customizable landing-page layouts, colour themes, and component galleries ready to match a community&amp;rsquo;s branding, it&amp;rsquo;s now easier than ever to couple a hub with its own co-located narrative content.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network can learn how to use this in
&lt;a href="https://docs.2i2c.org/admin/howto/monitoring/cost-attribution/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our user guide to documentation and sharing&lt;/a>. See
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/jb-for-communities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >this blog post for an announcement&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">
A better onboarding experience for our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We have been working on a streamlined onboarding experience for communities, smoothing out the process of gathering requirements, customizing a hub for the community&amp;rsquo;s specific needs, and delivering new hubs more rapidly. We will be rolling out this process in the next few weeks for new communities onboarding the 2i2c network, and aim to continue learning and refining this process to deliver a faster, smoother onboarding experience for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ Members of 2i2c&amp;rsquo;s community network will see &lt;strong>changes to our process&lt;/strong> over the coming months that increase the speed and ease of hub delivery.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="efforts-to-improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">
Efforts to improve and formalize the services we deliver to our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#efforts-to-improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As 2i2c has grown over the past few years, it organically developed internal processes for handling common tasks such as the management, rollout and maintenance of hubs, as well as expect consulting to help our communities get the most value out of their hubs. Earlier in the year, we realised it was time to review and refine these processes to better serve our growing community network. As a result of this exercise, we now have tighter service definitions and best practices which clarify what service levels our communities can expect, and how we can internally meet those expectations. We will be publishing our service definitions in the coming months as they are finalized, to ensure full transparency with our communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>⭐ You can learn more about our efforts to standardize and scale our services by
&lt;a href="http://2i2c.org/blog" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >following the 2i2c blog&lt;/a>, where we&amp;rsquo;ll share our work as it stabilizes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q3">
Another update coming in Q3
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q3">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll be announcing the focus for our next quarter in a follow-up post, so stay tuned for our next roadmap update, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfo6JFr9L5gEFpk_QjoR23YZ9GHXYaO-3WZWZV3qRz8pj7dbg/viewform?usp=dialog" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >let us know what you think&lt;/a> of our direction - we welcome your feedback!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Thanks to
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> for core support to 2i2c which funds this strategic and organizational work.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Our Product and Service goals for Q2 2025</title><link>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q2-product-goals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q2-product-goals/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>As we head into Q2 of 2025, we continue to focus our work delivering on a small set of core themes that reflect our communities’ most pressing needs. As a part of this process, we want to continue sharing our platform and service goals in an effort to remain transparent, as well as to provide our communities with an opportunity to give us feedback on our direction, and on what’s important for them. See
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/q1-product-goals/" >last quarter’s product goals here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following themes are not guarantees, but should provide a high level view on how we plan to improve our product and services offerings in the next quarter. &lt;strong>If your organization has funding available to support any of the enhancements below,
&lt;a href="https://forms.fillout.com/t/uQHVMkgvsuus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >reach out to us&lt;/a> and we can discuss how you can shape our priorities and outcomes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="give-administrators-more-control">
Give administrators more control
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#give-administrators-more-control">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The implementation of
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2025/per-user-storage-quota-gcp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >per-user storage quotas&lt;/a> in Q1 was the start of a set of product initiatives aimed at giving hub administrators more control and peace of mind over unexpected cost overruns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aim to continue giving administrators more control by implementing the ability to &lt;strong>associate users with groups for usage monitoring&lt;/strong>, and as a foundation for future improvements which will deliver &lt;strong>group-level management of storage quotas,&lt;/strong> and later Compute and Dask quotas.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">
Improve creating and sharing custom environments
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improve-creating-and-sharing-custom-environments">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>One of the wonderful things about shared open source JupyterHub infrastructure is that it allows community members to share their projects with each other in ways that ensure the work can be fully experienced by the recipient, complete with fully executable content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Q2, we aim to improve the ability for hub users to &lt;strong>build custom environments in their hubs&lt;/strong>, and later to easily &lt;strong>share those custom environments with others&lt;/strong>, ensuring their entire toolchain is replicated in full.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">
Out-of-the-box Jupyter Book support
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#out-of-the-box-jupyter-book-support">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We have been working on scoping and building a default JupyterBook implementation
&lt;a href="http://mystmd.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >using the new MyST document engine&lt;/a>, aiming to deliver a default set of tools for &lt;strong>authoring and sharing documentation&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>customizable landing pages&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>interactive training materials&lt;/strong> out of the box with new hub deployments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Q1 we delivered improvements to the JupyterBook launching interface to allow for &lt;strong>automatic hub type detection&lt;/strong>, as well as &lt;strong>landing page components, theming capabilities, galleries and more&lt;/strong>. We aim to complete this work in Q2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">
A better onboarding experience for our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#a-better-onboarding-experience-for-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As more communities in the research and education space join the 2i2c community network, it’s important for us to be ready to deliver the best value we can for them at scale. To that end, we’re &lt;strong>streamlining the processes we use to onboard our communities&lt;/strong>, improving the touchpoints through which we engage with them when they join our community network, and ensuring we create opportunities to better understand their needs in order to set them up for success with their hubs right from the start.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">
Improve and formalize the services we deliver to our communities
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#improve-and-formalize-the-services-we-deliver-to-our-communities">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Together with an improved onboarding experience, we aim to improve how we deliver other key services to our communities, including &lt;strong>expert consulting, hub management, and technical support&lt;/strong>, with the aim to offer more scalable, high-value services to address the needs of our communities in a sustainable way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the goals of this service revamp will include improving triaging of support tickets, shortening our issue response time, and providing our community champions with dedicated expertise on subjects including open source science and tools, community participation in open science, fundraising and grantsmanship co-creation, engineering consultancy and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="another-update-coming-in-q3">
Another update coming in Q3
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#another-update-coming-in-q3">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We’ll use this blog post as an informal roadmap of our product goals for the quarter, striving to advance as many of the outlined areas as possible. During our Q3 planning, we’ll reflect on the achievements made in line with this initiative and share a progress update with our community. Keep an eye out for more details!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">
Acknowledgements
&lt;a class="header-anchor" href="#acknowledgements">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our strategic and organization-level work is supported by a grant from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/collaborators/navigation/" >The Navigation Fund&lt;/a> and fees from
&lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/members/" >our member organizations&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>